# Jonathan Oliveira

Software Engineer

Passionate Software Engineer with 9+ years of experience. Working professionally as full-stack developer for 6+ years, focused on Java, Spring, AngularJS, HTML. Fast learner, software craftsmanship believer, problem-solver with can-do attitude, willing to deliver high quality software.



Maringa, Brazil

Maringa, Brazil

contato@jonathanoliveira.com

+55 44 9946-2606

1844 West 7th Avenue, Vancouver, BC

jonathan oliveira

# Work Experience

03/2015 - Present

#### Software Engineer

investor\$Tec @ investor\$Inc (personal project)

Real State Management Software for an international real estate advisory company.

- Displayed a really full stack role, from requirements gathering and project management to coding, deployment and server administration.
- Achieved fully continuous integration and continuous deploy environment with Bitbucket, Codeship and Heroku with virtually 100% app uptime.
- Managed many project challenges, such as cloud databases and large files and images uploads to the cloud (over 18k images).
- Automated several marketing processes such as brochure generation and images manipulations.
- Developed a REST API to integrate data to different websites.

Contact: Leandro Teles - teles@investorsinc.com.br

08/2014 - Present Maringa, Brazil

# Software Engineer

Objective Solutions

http://www.objective.com.br/

#### Tasks/Achievements

- Participated in the development and maintenance of a large CRM & billing system with Java and internal frameworks.
- Worked with several satellite systems with different technologies such as Javascript, JSF, and HTML/CSS.
- Took the initiative to change technologies of a JSF project to AngularJS, meeting client's tight deadlines and budget requirements.
- Taught AngularJS and Spring to the other team members.
- Member of a development team with strong agile practices such as SCRUM, pair programming, code review, CI, XP and Kanban.

Contact: Joel Matsu - +55 44 9106-5675

06/2013 - 08/2014

## Senior Java Developer

DB1 Global Software

http://www.db1.com.br

- Participated in outsourcing projects, with Java, defining architecture, programming, delegating tasks and managing follow-ups with other programmers.
- Automated several internal HR processes by making surveys, analyzing processes and developing a software to help HR operate more efficiently.
- Worked as a SCRUM Master of the development team and performed tasks of lesser complexity inherent in project management.
- Participated in an innovation project conducted internally with "My Loyalty Card".

Contact: Edoil Barros - +55 44 9125-1206

## Education

01/2006 - 12/2014

# **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science** State University of Maringa

#### Courses

- Compilers
- Artificial intelligence
- Programming languages
- Software engineering
- Algorithms
- Algorithms analysis

# Skills & Competences

Mobile dev	elopment (Ioni	c)		
Java/Sprin	g			
AngularJS				
Javascript,	/HTML/CSS		_	
SQL				
.Net				
UX/UI desi	gn			
Codeship/I	Heroku			
Git/SVN				
Project ma	nagement			

# **Personal Projects**

My Loyalty Card

 Simple desktop app for managing loyalty cards and customers points for restaurants and retailers in general.

#### **NetAnimations**

• Learning Object Repository of Computer Networking discipline of Computer Science course at State University of Maringá. Mobile app built with Ionic.

### My Games App

• Simple app to register, keep track and share my platforms and games. Building with Ionic Framework.

# Languages

Portuguese

Native or Bilingual

**Enalish** 

Upper-intermediate

Spanish

Beginner

# Interests

Software craftsmanship | Entrepreneurship | Frameworks | Games | Web development |

Cloud computing | IoT | CI & CD |

Personal finances | Guitar solos